Okay, we're on a call to order the regular city council meeting for today's date and time.
Item two is public input and on schedule personal appearances.
So I don't see the one in the audience.
So I'm going to move to item three, which can send agenda.
Item four through eight.
Staff of recommending for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items,
we're going to take motion to approve the consent agenda as recommended.
Second, roll call please.
Item nine is the same issue that we just discussed.
I believe.
Okay, and the SUA meeting, which is, this is an ordinance 2019 01,
a mending section 2460.
I have one more question and there are fuel costs.
I know they were expanding into natural gas and coal.
So the, the power that we purchased for city.
My emits all hydro.
Is that right?
There's a mixture.
It's a mixture of it.
Actually, coal, mostly gas, coal, hydro, we unpack.
And it also, we have a conversation, which is not a deal, but that's a hydro.
Yeah, yeah.
It seems like we have plenty of water to supply the hydro.
So I think.
The total hydro generation, don't need about 250 megawatts.
What is that as a percent of their total generation?
About 10 percent.
In coal, they shut down.
Are they retrofitted a coal firecrank?
Two.
The Giorde 2 unit is running Giorde 1 in shut down.
And it's basically moth all the right now.
And we, we discussed, we were just going to discuss.
There's a great detail in Giorde A.
What would we do?
Let's scrubbers on everything.
Are we built a gas fire fire plant?
Oh, it was more than the station.
We all ever made.
It was built a gas fire fire plant.
I think the coal was, uh, high sulfur.
Yeah.
The high sulfur one was, uh, Giorde A2 was built with scrubbers on it.
So they shut it down.
And as it was, the only had to spend about 300 million dollars on Giorde A2
to fix the scrubbers on it for the EPA.
Thank you.
Mr.
You mean other questions on item nine?
If not, do we have a most to approve?
Ordance 2019 01.
Thank you.
Mr.
You mean other questions on item nine?
If not, do we have a most to approve?
Ordance 2019 01.
And a second.
Second.
We'll call please.
Or get a question.
Aye.
Forster.
list. Hi, and item 10 is emergency calls are related to the same
ordinance. Do we have a most to approve the emergency clause?
I'll make a motion. And I'll second that, Roko.
I'll show. Hi.
Forester.
I work it.
Okay, I remember 11 is ordinance 2019-02 created an
section 24-3 right of entry, article 1 in general of chapter 24 for the purpose of
accessing utility department equipment providing several
guilty and establishing an effective date.
Hi.
What's all that mean?
Well, the next one.
The other I have been working on updating the utility
the customer service manual.
And we found two areas. One, we were looking for the right
of the right of entry ordinance.
And then we discovered that back in September that ordinance was actually
really never removed.
Some other changes. I think it's the building because.
So we went back and we asked the department and they said, well,
in our notes, we showed that the intention was to put those that right of
entry into utility chapter 24, which is what we should be.
So that's what we're asking is to re-establish it back.
It allows our reader readers to get on the property and read the
readers, maintain the readers.
You know, let's say they're going to want them to get on the property and
take responsibility to their readers.
So we didn't burden lady to leave that.
Or it was purposefully.
But the communication didn't happen to say.
It would just turn follow up.
Yeah.
Any concerns?
No, not at all.
In fact, if anything on the this side of the following item,
we have emergency clauses as we need to have something like this in the
ordinance.
So our people go in and read these readers side.
So it is kind of a repair or anything else in getting it back in place.
Okay.
Any other questions?
We have most to approve item 11, which is 29.
So to.
Any motion?
Second.
Local employees.
Worcester.
Work in.
Western.
High.
And then not in 12 is emergency clause related to the same ordinance.
Do we have a motion to approve?
I'll make a motion.
Second.
We'll call please.
Lewis.
Western.
Forester.
Work it.
So.
And then item 13 is ordinance.
2019 to show three.
Stablishing.
Section 27.
Six rates and charges within chapter 27.
Stablishing a dishonored payment fee.
You would probably know the term more return check.
But when we were looking into, it's really could be anything.
A credit card.
I could be returned.
So we found this term.
Or the return.
Or dishonored payment fee.
So that's what we chose to use as a language.
And back.
of the 17, there was what was called a non-rate rate study, and they looked at things like
our permitting fees, our licenses, I think they even looked at coal in rates, and that kind
of thing, and one of those things was a return check fee of $25. I looked back, I got the
minutes from that meeting, and the ordinance just didn't have this in there, and we all
thought it did. Again, when we were looking at the manual, after that ordinance couldn't find
it, so we realized it got missed, and we needed to have it in there. So it was recommended
in the rate study, the non-rate rate study we did, we just didn't actually get it into the
language into the old.
It was very large ordinance, and it just looks like it's kept this.
Any questions or concerns about inserting the dishonor payment fee?
Does fee still seem to yield?
And is this saying to check insufficient check?
It's the capers.
Do we have a motion to approve item 14?
I'll make the motion.
In 2019, there are show three, and a second, there will be a vote, please.
Well, it's been a short time.
For a certain list, I'll work it.
And then item 14 is the emergency hours related to the same board, so I'll make a motion to
approve.
Do we have a second?
Say.
World call, please.
For a start.
What's been?
Hi.
Lewis.
I'm four.
All right.
We're going to start.
Um, is an ordinance creating section 277 discretionary waiver of collection fees, for
chapter 27 for the purpose of authorizing the city manager, way of all of our portion
of collection fees, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera, and what are collection fees?
So if we send an account to collections, they haven't paid, and it was in a collection.
Strange things can happen.
Things we can't foresee.
An example I gave you was, someone that's a good payer, and they have several accounts, and
they pay auto draft, which is what we want them to do.
But if an account gets closed, say they have 15 accounts, but one of those accounts gets closed,
they're assuming that last payment is going to come out auto draft out of their bank account.
We don't do that on the last one, because most of those people move, and that makes
an account close.
So we would recommend keeping that or changing it to that.
But we would like to allow the authorities to see managers to waive fees if something like that
happens.
So life fees, et cetera?
Yeah, well, the collection fees, if there haven't been any, a lot of times we can just request
the collection to come back to us many times, but not all the time, without a fee to ask, but
it becomes us.
One of the things we had a situation like this that happened about a month ago, and
as staff, we all sat down and looked at this.
This is said, number one, the person that had happened to, I think any one of us in their position would have thought the same thing.
So, it's completely understandable.
Number two is looking at our process that works 99.9% of the time, great.
Try to change that to try to catch it.
Would have just changed our entire process.
So, the thought of having something like this, where rarely ever happens, but when it happens,
my ability to be able to wave it, but then on top of that, then I have to report it to you.
So, it's not something that would just be something that would just happen.
Just like we do on some of our other waivers, they're part of your report.
You're able to see them, you're able to oversee them to make sure that we're doing it on a proper basis.
That's probably the best way to be able to handle these situations.
And I agree, the distinction I'm trying to draw is, there's doesn't mention the late fees,
which are different with the collection, because we want to weigh those two.
I don't know if you currently have the discretion to do that.
On late fees, no.
So, do we need language on late fees, too, is what I'm asking?
You do.
You actually, currently, the city manager has the authority to weigh late fees and dispatch fees.
Okay.
Okay, sorry.
Sorry.
I want to make sure.
Okay.
This is the authority of the different.
The dispatch fees are what we have a tendency to wave quite a bit,
because people will realize, pay it on the spot, and we weight that fee for it.
Any other questions or for clarification or concerns?
And again, even on those dispatch fees, we just mentioned,
I think they're several in your agenda tonight that you see.
So, we report those as well.
So, do we have a motion to approve orders 2019-04?
And second.
Second roll, please.
Work it.
Aye.
Any new business, anyone?
Staff reports are in your pocket.
Any questions for staff?
Mayor?
Any council committee announcements?
Aye.
I do have one.
Good.
There is a...
Everybody that's in the city limits of my upper schools,
or that says there is an election tonight.
We have a school board.
We have a school board member.
And somebody ready to get some.
And the board?
Who has the clothes of that?
Yes.
Tell us about that.
And it's also a football and commerce and wine garden.
Anybody's got one?
Yeah.
And then also continue on with our 16-year celebration in the year.
The Saturday will be doing our unveiling of our first order of each statute.
That'll take place at one o'clock.
Awesome.
The beautiful way they're taking.
Yep.
Anything else?
Or announcements?
Any manager communication?
Amanda wanted me to remind everybody that they have the rodeo money.
I am a tech that's going to sell this week,
rode in my end as May 34th this year.
Let's hope the water stays low,
so we'll have plenty of place with parking
and everybody not have to reschedule it.
Also, they are say, you trip less a baseball turn
that this weekend, we have about 23 teams coming to town.
And at the end of this month, we have close to 40 teams
coming for a softball turn.
So check is keeping very, very busy,
and that is going well.
Let's bring clean up, just finished up.
And we have almost kind of imperious.
We actually didn't have as many loves as we have last year.
We had the 287 trash loads last year, 320.
We had 16 loads of yardways, or 16 tons.
Excuse me, last year we had 11.
So we went up in yardways, and only 831 tires
compared to last year, 1,312 tires.
But it's nice to know that we've got that out of our neighbor hoods
and into the proper ways to suppose the way it is.
We had a lot of people comment that they really appreciate
this program.
We are first numbers tons also on the 287.
I don't have the number of tons that we had at 20,
so we had 268 tons of trash.
I don't know what we had last year, but usually a load equals about a ton.
We had 287 loads, 268 tons.
I'm hoping those declining members of your assigned
that were making proper copies too.
That's your data.
I saw a lot of stuff piled out on the streets.
These are those something.
What we noticed, it seemed like we had fewer houses,
but the houses that had something piled out
had big bottles off of the streets.
That's not like.
Well, the more of the concerns that I have
that the name was brought to me and I know this convention
is that the people that are running in the truck,
that are loaded, so they're running and do the due diligence
of scrapping metal that most people wouldn't,
is that when they go through those piles,
it was essentially invoked into one-lilary
in somebody's yard, but then it all gets spread over here,
because they go through it in the day,
while somebody's at work, and they're just there for them.
I don't know what we can do to pursue that.
I don't know if that's a homeowner's, you know,
throw it all out to the night and the floor,
but you just, you never know when people go through it.
And the problem is, is that we don't know how quickly
we can get people's property.
If we tell somebody, put it out on a Wednesday,
and we might get bogged down, it might not be until Thursday
or Friday before we get to it.
And even the last few days, we usually go back to the neighborhood
because people will suddenly have a big pile
and say, oh, you forgot me.
So we go back and we pick it up and stuff.
I like the fact that some of us being up-cycle would be nice.
Yeah, as long as it's being up-cycle too,
the facility that needs to be up-cycle too.
it's being brought to another house and stored at your neighbor from the right.
We actually were able to be on top of that this year.
The first year when we got it restarted, we just moved it to another neighborhood.
And we kept that from happening.
But you're right when they go through and pick it, they don't have it.
They have a tendency sometimes not to leave it very nice.
I don't know how to use it, but I know it's just brought up.
But very appreciative of everybody I've talked to is thankful to that.
So I'm with you, man, I hope we're getting ahead of it.
Somebody posted on Facebook while back, they put stuff out like five years in a row.
And by the time our truck shows up, there's nothing left.
Well, the friend said, well, you've got two good stuff here, throw it away.
You know, barely.
The final thing I want to bring up is we're in budget seats.
And we do have an account under that we're going to have budget meetings on April 23rd, 24th and 25th at 530 p.m.
So I wanted to do this as a reminder, everybody could check their calendars.
And what we've usually had, what we all kind of hope is staff is that we go through the first day and we're okay.
But if we need to continue on, we have the 24th and the 25th to work on as well.
I know we're still kind of balancing budget, we still have even a couple departments to meet with yet.
So we're not completely ready ourselves.
And then along that line too, on the 16th, our next meeting will have the performer.
But it should always look forward to the kind of just that dashboard to see just how we're doing.
So now that we've based on last year and the audit that we just got.
That's exactly it.
So we're in that season as well.
And that's by report.
And I forgot to mention Sunday the branch in two, or we'll be at the call in the highest.
I think that would be a really neat show.
I'm looking forward to it.
It's the one that was rescheduled from last month because of the weather.
Some very good performers are coming.
Okay.
So item 20 says the meeting will be continued from council chambers and reconvened in the meeting room.
One for purposes of executive session.
And then we're going to adjourn and we'll take place in the meeting rooms.
Correct.
For all intents and purposes, this part of the meeting.
So I don't remember if we have to have a motion to continue the meeting.
I think we should have in the meeting.
Sorry.
That's what it means being reconvened.
Okay.
So I think I just announced that.
So we'll pack up and go.
I mean, I didn't even know you would.
Why?